# **SF.** front-end developer

## **Personal Information**

Stefan Frede contact [at] frede [dot] io +49-2051-4057910 Ehrenbergstraße 16a Scanbox #03611 10245 Berlin, Germany

#### **Skills**

HTML and (S)CSS
Responsive Web Design
Accessibility & Progressive Enhancement
Vanilla JavaScript
Web Components, LitElement, and lit-html
Jest, Mocha, and Chai
Redux and Redux-Saga
Webpack, Git, and Continuous Integration

#### **Kind Words**

Docker

I have worked together with Stefan on front-end projects for over 10 years, and the work was always done on time, on budget, and with a high degree of professionalism.

It's obvious he takes tremendous pride in his work, and I wouldn't hesitate to recommend or work with him again.

Thomas Nitsche, VP of Engineering, Experteer GmbH

Stefan has been supporting the company for years. He played a key role in developing our front-end further and always delivered on time and with great additional ideas.

I would definitely work with Stefan again and can highly recommend him.

Nina Zimmermann, CEO, tracdelight GmbH

#### **Personal Statement**

I'm a front-end developer with a focus on HTML, CSS, Accessibility and Progressive Enhancement. I specialize in reducing the complexity of modern "best practices" and like to limit myself to browser APIs when using JavaScript. I have been working in this business since 2004.

## Professional Experience (extract)

January 2020 - present

# T-Systems Multimedia Solutions GmbH | Freelance

• Built accessible components for a Salesforce application.

October 2019 - January 2020

#### Schweisthal Beschlag- und Schließtechnik GmbH | Freelance

· Built a web app to configure a locking system.

# November 2010 - January 2020

## 50plus-Treff GmbH | Freelance

- · Implemented the redesign to make the website mobile-friendly.
- · Maintained the website and implemented change requests.

## July 2019 - December 2019

#### Aboutbooks GmbH | Freelance

· Built promotions from publishers for new books.

#### July 2017 - September 2019

## ARIGO Software GmbH | Freelance

- · Built and maintained Web Components.
- Built an interface to communicate via a WebSocket connection with a REST API

#### November 2016 - Juni 2018

# tracdelight GmbH | Freelance

· Built and maintained brand promotions.

# November 2005 - July 2017

#### Experteer GmbH | Freelance

- · Built and maintained the web site.
- · Built inhouse tools.
- Implemented code standards.

#### Education

Macromedia - Akademie für neue Medien | 2001-2003

Digital Media Designer,